<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecology on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/ecology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ecology on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ecology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmolke et al (2010) Ecological models supporting environmental decision making: a strategy for the future</title>
      <link>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>de Vos Are Environmental Models Transparent and Reproducible?</title>
      <link>/posts/de-vos-are-environmental-models-transparent-and-reproducible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/de-vos-are-environmental-models-transparent-and-reproducible/</guid>
      <description>Problem: Why is transparency and reproducibility of environmental models important? Transparency and reproducibility are quintessential for facilitating assessment of model quality and suitability by both peer-reviewers, readers, and future users:  Page 1, 2018-06-20:  Environmental models are in fact applications of shared theories on how real-world systems are functioning.
 Because “Environmental models are in fact applications of shared theories on how real-world systems are functioning”, it is essential that “the underlying scientific theories they need to be evaluated and discussed among peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraser et al 2018 QRPs in Ecology and Evolution</title>
      <link>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Fraser, H. S., Parker, T. H., Nakagawa, S., Barnett, A., Fidler, F. (2018) Questionable Research Practices in Ecology and Evolution. doi: 10.17605/OSF.IO/AJYQG.
“Transformation process” of science communication is susceptible to confusion and corruption, has triggered both reflection and meta-research in other disciplines.
Forstmeier et al [8]:
Individual research practice is embedded in a broader culture, and promoite conditions of publication bias and type 1 errors. ‘Questionable research practices’ are fostered under conditions of publication bias, inflating false postive rates in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cullina et al 2018 Navigating the unfolding open data landscape in ecology and evolution</title>
      <link>/posts/cullina-et-al-2018-navigating-the-unfolding-open-data-landscape-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/cullina-et-al-2018-navigating-the-unfolding-open-data-landscape-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>The open data movement has the capacity to provide new and powerful insights into complex systems, in ecology and evolution. However, in ecology and evolution there has not been great uptake / implementation of open data to the extent seen in other disciplines (e.g. medicine, climate sciences).
Why open data?
 identify broader eco evo processes across space, time, species reanalysing data using new statistical approaches error checking using existing data to answer new questions era of the Anthropocene: large, complicated questions with high degree of uncertainty requires combined data from multiple sources, and multidsciplinary data synthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nakagawa and Parker 2015</title>
      <link>/posts/nakagawa-and-parker-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/nakagawa-and-parker-2015/</guid>
      <description>Why do we replicate? Assess the validity of prior findings probe the generality of those findings   Levels of replication Exact (also known as “direct”): highest fidelity to the original work. But in ecology, usually can only be ‘close’ replications. Partial: there is a spectrum of partial replications, from close to limited. These have slight procedural differences. Conceptual: uses distinctly different study designs to test the same hypotheses. Quasi-replication (cross-species or system)   Assessing validity  Probing generality Conceptual replications: when results concur, we can define generality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systematic review methodologies for conservation and ecology</title>
      <link>/posts/systematic-review-methodologies-for-conservation-and-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/systematic-review-methodologies-for-conservation-and-ecology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic Review Methods Nakagawa and Poulin [-@Nakagawa:2012fl] recommend following the PRISMA statement, at least for meta-analyses in ecology and evolution.
PRISMA
Checklist here: http://www.prisma-statement.org/documents/PRISMA%202009%20checklist.pdf
Cochrane Review
Manual broken down into two phases of the review: 1. Developing Protocol of the review 2. Conducting Review
Writing review protocol - Formulating review questions, predefining objectives. - Medicine focused, emphasis on reporting adverse effects, on consumer needs - Choosing &amp;lsquo;outcomes&amp;rsquo;of interest (Mandatory). Assessing risk of bias of studies included in the review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meeting Fiona Hannah 1st March 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-fiona-hannah-1st-march-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-fiona-hannah-1st-march-18/</guid>
      <description>To date:
Have been trying to determine the scope of the project. Want to look at the reproducibility of decision support tools
 what elements of existing reproducibility literature apply to this context?
 do we need a new set of criteria? Much of the repro literature especially in ecology seems to be focused on NHST, but this statistical tool is rarely used in decision science, instead it might often rely on the outputs of other studies that utilise them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Hannah</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-hannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-hannah/</guid>
      <description>See Steve&amp;rsquo;s guidelines around meta-analysis from medicine. Hannah&amp;rsquo;s criteria. Conservation Biology guidelines. Guidelines / checkpoints are just around transparency. No actual checking of reproducibility.
How do decisions vs. models differ? What is particular about my problem context? values, preferences. Process vs. decision model - problem is often split into two. Decision tools as models more complex, involve not just a model of the system / domain (including decision elements), but capturing objectives, alternatives, eliciting expert judgment, involving many stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madin (2007) Advancing ecological research with ontologies</title>
      <link>/posts/madin-2007-advancing-ecological-research-with-ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/madin-2007-advancing-ecological-research-with-ontologies/</guid>
      <description>(Madin et al. 2008)
Why are ontologies relevant to ecology? Issue of effectively locating scientific data is hampered because our current approaches for describing it rely on the “ad hoc use of user-supplied keywords, and do not ensure that such terms are defined and used consistently.” The same is true when searching for relevant data, “users supply their own search terms, which are then matched against keywords assigned to datasets”. Ecology is particularly prone to this problem, and many terms often have multiple and variable meanings in different contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hart - Towards a more reproducible ecology</title>
      <link>/posts/hart-towards-a-more-reproducible-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/hart-towards-a-more-reproducible-ecology/</guid>
      <description>Borregaard, M. K., Hart, E. M. (2018) Towards a more reproducible ecology. httpwww.ecography.orgblogtowards-more-reproducible-ecology, 1–9.
This is an editorial intro to the special edition of ecography dedicated to reproducible methods in ecology..
Page 1 Page 1, Red, Text, 2018-02-20: State of ecological research and analyses has changed.
Page 1, Red, Highlight, 2018-02-20:  A new paradigm has emerged, where individual scientists download, curate and share large amounts of data and analyse it using reproducible software packages and scripts written in languages such as R, Python and Julia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>