<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Practice on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/research-practice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Practice on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/research-practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dormann et al (2018) Biotic interactions in species distribution modelling\: 10 questions to guide interpretations and avoid false conclusions</title>
      <link>/posts/dormann-et-al-2018-biotic-interactions-in-species-distribution-modelling-10-questions-to-guide-interpretations-and-avoid-false-conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/dormann-et-al-2018-biotic-interactions-in-species-distribution-modelling-10-questions-to-guide-interpretations-and-avoid-false-conclusions/</guid>
      <description>Problem The authors aim to address the problem of false conclusions arisng during inference of joint species distribution models – specifically, false conclusions of biotic interactions.
Approach The authors conduct a review of joint species distribution modelling to identify (from caveats and other issues ear-marked in the source papers) potential factors that confound interpretation of analyses. Next, they develop a series of questions that can be asked by the analyst and also the reviewer to guide interpretation of conclusions – are the conclusions about biotic interactions plausible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Perspectives in Statistics Education</title>
      <link>/posts/new-perspectives-in-statistics-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/new-perspectives-in-statistics-education/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming events: Statistical Society of Australia (SSA), Biostatistics bonanza. August 23.
Sue Finch: “Back to basics? Identifying educational needs through statistical consulting” People who come to consulting come with real need - come with an applied problem. How can we use this to inform new generation of statistical training for researchers?
Break down research cycle using PPDAC cycle used within statistical education (Wild and Pfannkuch). Process of statistical thinking when carrying out a statistical inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seaman &amp; Weber (2015) Undisclosed Flexibility in Computing and Reporting Structural Equation Models in Communication Science.</title>
      <link>/posts/seaman-c-s-weber-r-2015-undisclosed-flexibility-in-computing-and-reporting-structural-equation-models-in-communication-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/seaman-c-s-weber-r-2015-undisclosed-flexibility-in-computing-and-reporting-structural-equation-models-in-communication-science/</guid>
      <description>Summary This paper is a systematic review (or ‘methodological review’ in their tersm) of both QRPs and bad modelling practice in structural equation modelling within the field of communication. They don’t use the term ‘Questionable Research Practices’, however, they do explicitly look at practices falling under the QRP banner, including cherry-picking, HARKing, and researcher degrees of freedom. Importantly, this paper is really useful to me because they examine these questionable research practices in a modelling framework outside of the non-hypothetico-deductive scientific model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmolke et al (2010) Ecological models supporting environmental decision making: a strategy for the future</title>
      <link>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QRPs Study Planning</title>
      <link>/posts/qrps-study-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/qrps-study-planning/</guid>
      <description>QRPs for non-hypothesis testing research in Ecology and Conservation Decision Making Problem and Background:
The reproducibility literature has focused exclusively on hypothesis-testing, whether that be Bayesian or frequentist. This also applies to initial research focusing on ecology and evolution. However, Fidler (2016) correctly identifies that in applied ecological research, particularly in conservation science, non-hypothesis testing methods, such as decision-theory, cost-effectiveness analysis, optimization and other scientific computing methods are common. These approaches come with their own set of reproducibility issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraser et al 2018 QRPs in Ecology and Evolution</title>
      <link>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Fraser, H. S., Parker, T. H., Nakagawa, S., Barnett, A., Fidler, F. (2018) Questionable Research Practices in Ecology and Evolution. doi: 10.17605/OSF.IO/AJYQG.
“Transformation process” of science communication is susceptible to confusion and corruption, has triggered both reflection and meta-research in other disciplines.
Forstmeier et al [8]:
Individual research practice is embedded in a broader culture, and promoite conditions of publication bias and type 1 errors. ‘Questionable research practices’ are fostered under conditions of publication bias, inflating false postive rates in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retreat Reproducibility Session</title>
      <link>/posts/retreat-reproducibility-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/retreat-reproducibility-session/</guid>
      <description>Session Planning Focus: Reproducibility in practice - QRPs.
Session aim: To help spread awareness among Qaecologists and Cebranalysts about reproducibility issues in our research practices. And then possibly provide people with the tools / solutions to overcome some of these issues.
Format: not a lecture, not an unstructured discussion.
Length 90 minutes.
Introduction: 15 minutes Introductory talk with a few slides . Led by Fiona and Hannah.
Intro by Fiona, perhaps talking about why reproducibility is important to us as ecologists, the state of reproducibility in eco/evo, an in the context of other dsciplines?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madin (2007) Advancing ecological research with ontologies</title>
      <link>/posts/madin-2007-advancing-ecological-research-with-ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/madin-2007-advancing-ecological-research-with-ontologies/</guid>
      <description>(Madin et al. 2008)
Why are ontologies relevant to ecology? Issue of effectively locating scientific data is hampered because our current approaches for describing it rely on the “ad hoc use of user-supplied keywords, and do not ensure that such terms are defined and used consistently.” The same is true when searching for relevant data, “users supply their own search terms, which are then matched against keywords assigned to datasets”. Ecology is particularly prone to this problem, and many terms often have multiple and variable meanings in different contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>