<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transparency on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/transparency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transparency on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/transparency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seaman &amp; Weber (2015) Undisclosed Flexibility in Computing and Reporting Structural Equation Models in Communication Science.</title>
      <link>/posts/seaman-c-s-weber-r-2015-undisclosed-flexibility-in-computing-and-reporting-structural-equation-models-in-communication-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/seaman-c-s-weber-r-2015-undisclosed-flexibility-in-computing-and-reporting-structural-equation-models-in-communication-science/</guid>
      <description>Summary This paper is a systematic review (or ‘methodological review’ in their tersm) of both QRPs and bad modelling practice in structural equation modelling within the field of communication. They don’t use the term ‘Questionable Research Practices’, however, they do explicitly look at practices falling under the QRP banner, including cherry-picking, HARKing, and researcher degrees of freedom. Importantly, this paper is really useful to me because they examine these questionable research practices in a modelling framework outside of the non-hypothetico-deductive scientific model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmolke et al (2010) Ecological models supporting environmental decision making: a strategy for the future</title>
      <link>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>de Vos Are Environmental Models Transparent and Reproducible?</title>
      <link>/posts/de-vos-are-environmental-models-transparent-and-reproducible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/de-vos-are-environmental-models-transparent-and-reproducible/</guid>
      <description>Problem: Why is transparency and reproducibility of environmental models important? Transparency and reproducibility are quintessential for facilitating assessment of model quality and suitability by both peer-reviewers, readers, and future users:  Page 1, 2018-06-20:  Environmental models are in fact applications of shared theories on how real-world systems are functioning.
 Because “Environmental models are in fact applications of shared theories on how real-world systems are functioning”, it is essential that “the underlying scientific theories they need to be evaluated and discussed among peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QRPs Study Planning</title>
      <link>/posts/qrps-study-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/qrps-study-planning/</guid>
      <description>QRPs for non-hypothesis testing research in Ecology and Conservation Decision Making Problem and Background:
The reproducibility literature has focused exclusively on hypothesis-testing, whether that be Bayesian or frequentist. This also applies to initial research focusing on ecology and evolution. However, Fidler (2016) correctly identifies that in applied ecological research, particularly in conservation science, non-hypothesis testing methods, such as decision-theory, cost-effectiveness analysis, optimization and other scientific computing methods are common. These approaches come with their own set of reproducibility issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraser et al 2018 QRPs in Ecology and Evolution</title>
      <link>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Fraser, H. S., Parker, T. H., Nakagawa, S., Barnett, A., Fidler, F. (2018) Questionable Research Practices in Ecology and Evolution. doi: 10.17605/OSF.IO/AJYQG.
“Transformation process” of science communication is susceptible to confusion and corruption, has triggered both reflection and meta-research in other disciplines.
Forstmeier et al [8]:
Individual research practice is embedded in a broader culture, and promoite conditions of publication bias and type 1 errors. ‘Questionable research practices’ are fostered under conditions of publication bias, inflating false postive rates in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retreat Reproducibility Session</title>
      <link>/posts/retreat-reproducibility-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/retreat-reproducibility-session/</guid>
      <description>Session Planning Focus: Reproducibility in practice - QRPs.
Session aim: To help spread awareness among Qaecologists and Cebranalysts about reproducibility issues in our research practices. And then possibly provide people with the tools / solutions to overcome some of these issues.
Format: not a lecture, not an unstructured discussion.
Length 90 minutes.
Introduction: 15 minutes Introductory talk with a few slides . Led by Fiona and Hannah.
Intro by Fiona, perhaps talking about why reproducibility is important to us as ecologists, the state of reproducibility in eco/evo, an in the context of other dsciplines?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gardner et al. 2018 Decision Complacency and Conservation Planning</title>
      <link>/posts/gardner-et-al-2018-decision-complacency-and-conservation-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/gardner-et-al-2018-decision-complacency-and-conservation-planning/</guid>
      <description>Gardner et al. (2018) add to knowledge-doing gap literature by defining and exemplifying what they call “Decision Complacency”
 The non-use of evidence or systematic processes to make decisions.
 Contextualising decision complacency in the knowledge-doing gap:
Researcher-practitioner divide: the case where researchers do not meet the needs of practitioners such that the information provided by conservation scientists does not allow decision-makers or practitioners to make sufficiently evidence-based decisions Evidence Complacency: Sutherland and Wordley (2017) describe a different angle of the researcher-practitioner divide where practitioners don’t use or seek available evidence, and/or don’t test the impact of their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fidler 2017 Metaresearch in ecology</title>
      <link>/posts/fidler-2017-metaresearch-in-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/fidler-2017-metaresearch-in-ecology/</guid>
      <description>Fidler, F., Chee, Y. E., Wintle, B. A., Burgman, M. A., McCarthy, M. A., Gordon, A. (2017) Metaresearch for Evaluating Reproducibility in Ecology and Evolution. BioScience doi: 10.1093/biosci/biw159.
Demonstrate that ecology and evolution as disciplines are at risk of a having low rates of reproducibility, aka a &amp;lsquo;reproducibility crisis&amp;rsquo; as others have termed it. The paper sets out to identify the different ways in which ecology is likely to have a reproducibility problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>