<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peer Review on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/peer-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peer Review on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/peer-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dormann et al (2018) Biotic interactions in species distribution modelling\: 10 questions to guide interpretations and avoid false conclusions</title>
      <link>/posts/dormann-et-al-2018-biotic-interactions-in-species-distribution-modelling-10-questions-to-guide-interpretations-and-avoid-false-conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/dormann-et-al-2018-biotic-interactions-in-species-distribution-modelling-10-questions-to-guide-interpretations-and-avoid-false-conclusions/</guid>
      <description>Problem The authors aim to address the problem of false conclusions arisng during inference of joint species distribution models – specifically, false conclusions of biotic interactions.
Approach The authors conduct a review of joint species distribution modelling to identify (from caveats and other issues ear-marked in the source papers) potential factors that confound interpretation of analyses. Next, they develop a series of questions that can be asked by the analyst and also the reviewer to guide interpretation of conclusions – are the conclusions about biotic interactions plausible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seaman &amp; Weber (2015) Undisclosed Flexibility in Computing and Reporting Structural Equation Models in Communication Science.</title>
      <link>/posts/seaman-c-s-weber-r-2015-undisclosed-flexibility-in-computing-and-reporting-structural-equation-models-in-communication-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/seaman-c-s-weber-r-2015-undisclosed-flexibility-in-computing-and-reporting-structural-equation-models-in-communication-science/</guid>
      <description>Summary This paper is a systematic review (or ‘methodological review’ in their tersm) of both QRPs and bad modelling practice in structural equation modelling within the field of communication. They don’t use the term ‘Questionable Research Practices’, however, they do explicitly look at practices falling under the QRP banner, including cherry-picking, HARKing, and researcher degrees of freedom. Importantly, this paper is really useful to me because they examine these questionable research practices in a modelling framework outside of the non-hypothetico-deductive scientific model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmolke et al (2010) Ecological models supporting environmental decision making: a strategy for the future</title>
      <link>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/schmolke-et-al-2010-ecological-models-supporting-environmental-decision-making-a-strategy-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>de Vos Are Environmental Models Transparent and Reproducible?</title>
      <link>/posts/de-vos-are-environmental-models-transparent-and-reproducible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/de-vos-are-environmental-models-transparent-and-reproducible/</guid>
      <description>Problem: Why is transparency and reproducibility of environmental models important? Transparency and reproducibility are quintessential for facilitating assessment of model quality and suitability by both peer-reviewers, readers, and future users:  Page 1, 2018-06-20:  Environmental models are in fact applications of shared theories on how real-world systems are functioning.
 Because “Environmental models are in fact applications of shared theories on how real-world systems are functioning”, it is essential that “the underlying scientific theories they need to be evaluated and discussed among peers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>