<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Data on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/open-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Data on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/open-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cullina et al 2018 Navigating the unfolding open data landscape in ecology and evolution</title>
      <link>/posts/cullina-et-al-2018-navigating-the-unfolding-open-data-landscape-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/cullina-et-al-2018-navigating-the-unfolding-open-data-landscape-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>The open data movement has the capacity to provide new and powerful insights into complex systems, in ecology and evolution. However, in ecology and evolution there has not been great uptake / implementation of open data to the extent seen in other disciplines (e.g. medicine, climate sciences).
Why open data?
 identify broader eco evo processes across space, time, species reanalysing data using new statistical approaches error checking using existing data to answer new questions era of the Anthropocene: large, complicated questions with high degree of uncertainty requires combined data from multiple sources, and multidsciplinary data synthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madin (2007) Advancing ecological research with ontologies</title>
      <link>/posts/madin-2007-advancing-ecological-research-with-ontologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/madin-2007-advancing-ecological-research-with-ontologies/</guid>
      <description>(Madin et al. 2008)
Why are ontologies relevant to ecology? Issue of effectively locating scientific data is hampered because our current approaches for describing it rely on the “ad hoc use of user-supplied keywords, and do not ensure that such terms are defined and used consistently.” The same is true when searching for relevant data, “users supply their own search terms, which are then matched against keywords assigned to datasets”. Ecology is particularly prone to this problem, and many terms often have multiple and variable meanings in different contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>