<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Replication on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/replication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Replication on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/replication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Perspectives in Statistics Education</title>
      <link>/posts/new-perspectives-in-statistics-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/new-perspectives-in-statistics-education/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming events: Statistical Society of Australia (SSA), Biostatistics bonanza. August 23.
Sue Finch: “Back to basics? Identifying educational needs through statistical consulting” People who come to consulting come with real need - come with an applied problem. How can we use this to inform new generation of statistical training for researchers?
Break down research cycle using PPDAC cycle used within statistical education (Wild and Pfannkuch). Process of statistical thinking when carrying out a statistical inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Committee Meeting</title>
      <link>/posts/advisory-committee-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/advisory-committee-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2, QRPs Scope Trying to cover the scope of the entire decision process might be too large for just one chapter. Just examining QRPs for system modelling is quite a task. PV suggested restricting the focus to decision tools and focussing on one application area, such as conservation planning / reserve design. This would also give more traction and uptake among ecologists. Conservation planning isn&amp;rsquo;t using the term &amp;lsquo;reproducibility&amp;rsquo; to describe their problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nakagawa and Parker 2015</title>
      <link>/posts/nakagawa-and-parker-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/nakagawa-and-parker-2015/</guid>
      <description>Why do we replicate? Assess the validity of prior findings probe the generality of those findings   Levels of replication Exact (also known as “direct”): highest fidelity to the original work. But in ecology, usually can only be ‘close’ replications. Partial: there is a spectrum of partial replications, from close to limited. These have slight procedural differences. Conceptual: uses distinctly different study designs to test the same hypotheses. Quasi-replication (cross-species or system)   Assessing validity  Probing generality Conceptual replications: when results concur, we can define generality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>