<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>False Positive on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/false-positive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in False Positive on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/false-positive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesianism and questionable research practices</title>
      <link>/posts/bayesianism-and-questionable-research-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/bayesianism-and-questionable-research-practices/</guid>
      <description>What are the different model types / applications used in ecology / conservation? what is the process for deriving, evaluating, and reporting these models? At what point in the process might QRPs arise? Can the same QRP arise at different points during the analysis?  Next actions
 read the stopping rules paper I just imported into papers add prior selection / weighting and other qaeco retreat points to the table below can we generalise overarching workflows across methods?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simonsohn (2014) </title>
      <link>/posts/simonsohn-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/simonsohn-2014/</guid>
      <description>Relationship to frequentist analyses, and the potential for P-hacking Simsonohn (2014) ran two computational experiments looking at the effects of p-hacking practices on the chance of a type I error for both Bayesian confidence intervals and Bayes Factors. He compared the Bayesian methods to the frequentist methods for each.
Bayesian confidence intervals are mathematically equivalent to frequentist confidence intervals. The only real difference is that their philosophical interpretation is different (and under both inference frameworks, normality is assumed).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>