<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/categories/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshop on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ACEMS workshop: modelling, experiments, data - what constitutes scientific evidence?</title>
      <link>/posts/acems-workshop-modelling-experiments-data-what-constitutes-scientific-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/acems-workshop-modelling-experiments-data-what-constitutes-scientific-evidence/</guid>
      <description>James McCaw: How models change the value of observational data? Empirical vs. theory driven research Physics is quintessential example of theory driven area. Psychology, if completely empirical and basic laws are unknown, psychology is trying to discover what the law is. Mathematical laws are used to analyse the data
Immunology - also a deeply theoretical or conceptually driven field. But the way that the science is done is completely empirical. Theory motivated, qualitative, conceptual model, analyse the data using ANOVA etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEBRA-workshop</title>
      <link>/posts/cebra-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/cebra-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Personal reflections on the CEBRA-SDM (pest-management climate modelling) workshop, emphasis on reproducibility.
Discussion with JE and JC Did I get what I need from the workshop, is it useful to me?
I’m going to assist James in collating all the butcher’s paper. From this I can attempt to generate a roadmap of the numerous subjective judgments people make during SDM. Then I will be able to map onto those decision points potential QRP analogues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open science in applied and use-inspired basic research</title>
      <link>/posts/open-science-in-applied-and-use-inspired-basic-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/open-science-in-applied-and-use-inspired-basic-research/</guid>
      <description>Stokes, D.E. (2011) Pasteur’s quadrant: Basic science and technological innovation. Brookings Institution PRess.
Pre-registration difficult when doing research outside of traditional confirmatory research, qualitative methods, exploratory research. How to make a priori hypotheses as transparent as possible.
Transparency is not enough. Problem of how to communicate your research to outsiders… how to ensure that they can make appropriate inferences. Translational value –&amp;gt; how do we incorporate practices that maximise this value?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retreat QRP session</title>
      <link>/posts/retreat-qrp-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/retreat-qrp-session/</guid>
      <description>Summary and purpose of the workshop: We ran a workshop where we hosted small discussions attempting to propose questionable research practices that arise in ecological and conservation research using non-frequentist and/or non hypothetico-deductive inquiry.
The purpose of the workshop was two-fold:
To bring awareness to our research group of QRPs for the types of work relevant to the group, and to consider how reproducibility issues might affect us, even if reproducibility research seems irrelevant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bioinformatics workshop dockerisation</title>
      <link>/posts/bioinformatics-workshop-dockerisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/bioinformatics-workshop-dockerisation/</guid>
      <description>Slides are here: http://melbournebioinformatics.github.io/MelBioInf_docs/tutorials/docker/media/index.html#47
Docker: libraries and operating system included as well (as application). ALl dependencies distributed. AND docker containers are cross-platform. == Portable. Distributable: can store images on the docker cloud.
Docker containers can&amp;rsquo;t access host-system&amp;rsquo;s files (good for security), but limits some use-cases (especially where command line utilities used).
Docker containers are very lightweight (no overhead like what virtual machines have). Docker can share libraries&amp;hellip; so if have 3 containers running ubuntu, they all share this code, whereas VM&amp;rsquo;s have to have 3 versions, one for each instance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>