<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication bias on research notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/publication-bias/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publication bias on research notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Elise Gould</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/publication-bias/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraser et al 2018 QRPs in Ecology and Evolution</title>
      <link>/post/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Fraser, H. S., Parker, T. H., Nakagawa, S., Barnett, A., Fidler, F. (2018) Questionable Research Practices in Ecology and Evolution. doi: 10.17605/OSF.IO/AJYQG.
“Transformation process” of science communication is susceptible to confusion and corruption, has triggered both reflection and meta-research in other disciplines.
Forstmeier et al [8]:
Individual research practice is embedded in a broader culture, and promoite conditions of publication bias and type 1 errors. ‘Questionable research practices’ are fostered under conditions of publication bias, inflating false postive rates in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fidler 2017 Metaresearch in ecology</title>
      <link>/post/fidler-2017-metaresearch-in-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fidler-2017-metaresearch-in-ecology/</guid>
      <description>Fidler, F., Chee, Y. E., Wintle, B. A., Burgman, M. A., McCarthy, M. A., Gordon, A. (2017) Metaresearch for Evaluating Reproducibility in Ecology and Evolution. BioScience doi: 10.1093/biosci/biw159.
Demonstrate that ecology and evolution as disciplines are at risk of a having low rates of reproducibility, aka a &amp;lsquo;reproducibility crisis&amp;rsquo; as others have termed it. The paper sets out to identify the different ways in which ecology is likely to have a reproducibility problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>