<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reproducibility Roadmap on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/reproducibility-roadmap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reproducibility Roadmap on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/reproducibility-roadmap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>proposal out-takes</title>
      <link>/posts/proposal_outtakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/proposal_outtakes/</guid>
      <description>Unpacking what this (“reproducibility issues”) means … what do we need to know? what is my task a. how to measure the likely reproducibility of a study b. what is the function / role of different types of replications in terms of what they tell us about the broader state of the literature (validity, generalisations) c.
how widespread the reproducibility issues identified in part I. The work from the first aim will help to inform the scoping rules and coding criteria for the systematic review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QRP and Biases Roadmap</title>
      <link>/posts/qrp_roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/qrp_roadmap/</guid>
      <description>Goal I want to generate a “roadmap” of the sources of bias and questionable research practices (QRPs) that I think are frequently encountered when developing D in applied ecology / conservation. These biases will reduce the reproducibility of of a given decision support tool. Identifying where in the DST development process particular biases are likely to occur should serve as a launching point for proposing solutions towards minimising their occurrence and therefore increasing the reproducibility of DSTs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>