<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Evidence-based on research notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/evidence-based/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Evidence-based on research notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Elise Gould</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/evidence-based/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gardner et al. 2018 Decision Complacency and Conservation Planning</title>
      <link>/post/gardner-et-al-2018-decision-complacency-and-conservation-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gardner-et-al-2018-decision-complacency-and-conservation-planning/</guid>
      <description>Gardner et al. (2018) add to knowledge-doing gap literature by defining and exemplifying what they call “Decision Complacency”
 The non-use of evidence or systematic processes to make decisions.
 Contextualising decision complacency in the knowledge-doing gap:
Researcher-practitioner divide: the case where researchers do not meet the needs of practitioners such that the information provided by conservation scientists does not allow decision-makers or practitioners to make sufficiently evidence-based decisions Evidence Complacency: Sutherland and Wordley (2017) describe a different angle of the researcher-practitioner divide where practitioners don’t use or seek available evidence, and/or don’t test the impact of their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law et al. (2017) Biol Con</title>
      <link>/post/law-et-al-2017-biol-con/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/law-et-al-2017-biol-con/</guid>
      <description>Law, E. A., Ferraro, P. J., Arcese, P., Bryan, B. A., Davis, K., Gordon, A., Holden, M. H., Iacona, G., Martinez, R. M., McAlpine, C. A., Rhodes, J. R., Sze, J. S., Wilson, K. A. (2017) Projecting the performance of conservation interventions. BIOC doi: 10.1016/j.biocon.2017.08.029.
Problem: Projecting the performance of conservation interventions Successful decision-making for environmental management requires reliable evidence for both the performance and efficacy of proposed conservation actions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>