<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research proposal on research notebook</title>
    <link>/categories/research-proposal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research proposal on research notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Elise Gould</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/research-proposal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fidler 2017 Metaresearch in ecology</title>
      <link>/post/fidler-2017-metaresearch-in-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fidler-2017-metaresearch-in-ecology/</guid>
      <description>Fidler, F., Chee, Y. E., Wintle, B. A., Burgman, M. A., McCarthy, M. A., Gordon, A. (2017) Metaresearch for Evaluating Reproducibility in Ecology and Evolution. BioScience doi: 10.1093/biosci/biw159.
Demonstrate that ecology and evolution as disciplines are at risk of a having low rates of reproducibility, aka a &amp;lsquo;reproducibility crisis&amp;rsquo; as others have termed it. The paper sets out to identify the different ways in which ecology is likely to have a reproducibility problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Research Proposal</title>
      <link>/project/reserach_proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/reserach_proposal/</guid>
      <description>Max 5 pages, 3000 - 4000 words. Send to committee and cc’d to rhd-biosciences@unimelb.edu.au
 are topic and aims well defined and achievable are the appropriate methods established or will they need to be developed does the student understand the relevant literature are there any intellectual property issues current / potential EHS issues?  Introduction  well-referenced intro that explains scientific context of project (1 - 3 pages)  Science is a cumulative process building upon previous research to develop knowledge, however, this process requires that the findings are both real, and replicable (Nakagawa and Parker 2015).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>research_proposal</title>
      <link>/project/reserach_proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/reserach_proposal/</guid>
      <description>Goal I want to generate a “roadmap” of the sources of bias and questionable research practices (QRPs) that I think are frequently encountered when developing D in applied ecology / conservation. These biases will reduce the reproducibility of of a given decision support tool. Identifying where in the DST development process particular biases are likely to occur should serve as a launching point for proposing solutions towards minimising their occurrence and therefore increasing the reproducibility of DSTs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>