<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Evolution on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Evolution on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraser et al 2018 QRPs in Ecology and Evolution</title>
      <link>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/fraser-et-al-2018-qrps-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Fraser, H. S., Parker, T. H., Nakagawa, S., Barnett, A., Fidler, F. (2018) Questionable Research Practices in Ecology and Evolution. doi: 10.17605/OSF.IO/AJYQG.
“Transformation process” of science communication is susceptible to confusion and corruption, has triggered both reflection and meta-research in other disciplines.
Forstmeier et al [8]:
Individual research practice is embedded in a broader culture, and promoite conditions of publication bias and type 1 errors. ‘Questionable research practices’ are fostered under conditions of publication bias, inflating false postive rates in the literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cullina et al 2018 Navigating the unfolding open data landscape in ecology and evolution</title>
      <link>/posts/cullina-et-al-2018-navigating-the-unfolding-open-data-landscape-in-ecology-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/cullina-et-al-2018-navigating-the-unfolding-open-data-landscape-in-ecology-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>The open data movement has the capacity to provide new and powerful insights into complex systems, in ecology and evolution. However, in ecology and evolution there has not been great uptake / implementation of open data to the extent seen in other disciplines (e.g. medicine, climate sciences).
Why open data?
 identify broader eco evo processes across space, time, species reanalysing data using new statistical approaches error checking using existing data to answer new questions era of the Anthropocene: large, complicated questions with high degree of uncertainty requires combined data from multiple sources, and multidsciplinary data synthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nakagawa and Parker 2015</title>
      <link>/posts/nakagawa-and-parker-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/nakagawa-and-parker-2015/</guid>
      <description>Why do we replicate? Assess the validity of prior findings probe the generality of those findings   Levels of replication Exact (also known as “direct”): highest fidelity to the original work. But in ecology, usually can only be ‘close’ replications. Partial: there is a spectrum of partial replications, from close to limited. These have slight procedural differences. Conceptual: uses distinctly different study designs to test the same hypotheses. Quasi-replication (cross-species or system)   Assessing validity  Probing generality Conceptual replications: when results concur, we can define generality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>