<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meeting on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/categories/meeting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meeting on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/meeting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018-09-08 meeting QRP survey design</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-qrp-survey-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-qrp-survey-design/</guid>
      <description>Themis, Ethics
 [x] Location / public / private [x] Named Researcher credentials and experience  RIOT accreditation counts for the training question. Just give one sentence spiel for the other questions. Survey Design Estimating Prevalence and Risk of QRPs \(Risk = Likelihood \times Consequence\)
Risk
% papers or researchers engaging in the practice.
If researchers:
 can compare the number of estimated vs. self-reported? Some interesting questions about whether self reporters estimate the prevalence to be greater than non-self reporters, is the self reported rate lower than the estimated rate?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retreat Reproducibility Session</title>
      <link>/posts/retreat-reproducibility-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/retreat-reproducibility-session/</guid>
      <description>Session Planning Focus: Reproducibility in practice - QRPs.
Session aim: To help spread awareness among Qaecologists and Cebranalysts about reproducibility issues in our research practices. And then possibly provide people with the tools / solutions to overcome some of these issues.
Format: not a lecture, not an unstructured discussion.
Length 90 minutes.
Introduction: 15 minutes Introductory talk with a few slides . Led by Fiona and Hannah.
Intro by Fiona, perhaps talking about why reproducibility is important to us as ecologists, the state of reproducibility in eco/evo, an in the context of other dsciplines?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meeting april 12 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-april-12-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-april-12-2018/</guid>
      <description>Planning the projects and the scope of the Phd (and the format for the thesis):
 Perfectly acceptable to have disparate projects / papers comprising the thesis, and bound together with a good introduction and conclusion. Don’t have to choose between different projects.  Good to try and sit with that tension, and not having to resolve it by having a neat / tightly fitting narrative thesis.
Hannah: working on structured decision making tool with Libby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meeting</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting/</guid>
      <description> Investigating appropriate systematic review methodologies Developing a framework / list of non-NHST reproducibility issues (QRP&amp;rsquo;s and other sources of bias) for decision-support tools &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; informing the coding criteria for systematic review    Fiona link.l  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meeting 15 March 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-15-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-15-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>Libby, Hannah present.
Exploring systematic review methods Add my notes from CJ meeting here.
Also see: BES - will be discussed in coding club / reading club. SER (Society of ecological restoration) -&amp;gt; Australian Chapter, SERA. Other disciplines where science / evidence is used in making decision s(Ecotoxicology / Biosecurity).
Authors who have worked on systematic reviews in ecology (@TODO): - Catherine Pickering - Robin Hale - W J Sutherland</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reading club reproducibility</title>
      <link>/posts/reading-club-reproducibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/reading-club-reproducibility/</guid>
      <description>BES Reproducibility guidelines.
Good for YOU, and for reproducibility.
Uptake in education: Fiona new reproducibility subject at the University.
Setting up a project / programming  Archive old papers + code: local folder (Nick) RANDOM SEED&amp;hellip; forgetting to set. Compounded by long run-times and large file-sizes.  Accessibility&amp;hellip; Barriers to startign work on reproducibility, but also, what are the bare minimum standards&amp;hellip; -&amp;gt; Little changes each new time.
Statistical abstinence vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meeting Fiona Hannah 1st March 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-fiona-hannah-1st-march-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-fiona-hannah-1st-march-18/</guid>
      <description>To date:
Have been trying to determine the scope of the project. Want to look at the reproducibility of decision support tools
 what elements of existing reproducibility literature apply to this context?
 do we need a new set of criteria? Much of the repro literature especially in ecology seems to be focused on NHST, but this statistical tool is rarely used in decision science, instead it might often rely on the outputs of other studies that utilise them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Hannah</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-hannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-hannah/</guid>
      <description>See Steve&amp;rsquo;s guidelines around meta-analysis from medicine. Hannah&amp;rsquo;s criteria. Conservation Biology guidelines. Guidelines / checkpoints are just around transparency. No actual checking of reproducibility.
How do decisions vs. models differ? What is particular about my problem context? values, preferences. Process vs. decision model - problem is often split into two. Decision tools as models more complex, involve not just a model of the system / domain (including decision elements), but capturing objectives, alternatives, eliciting expert judgment, involving many stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meeting</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting/</guid>
      <description> Activities in the last week  Trying to map out the landscape of reproducibility, in particular, within ecology.  What is the magnitude of the reproducibility crisis, do people even think we have one? What&amp;rsquo;s being done? Mostly focused on efforts by individuals or research groups, as well as institutional efforts, particularly emerging in the bioinformatics discipline and focusing on computational analysis workflows and data management.
 Is there really a differnce  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meeting Feb 15 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-feb-15-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-feb-15-2018/</guid>
      <description>activities -&amp;gt; working towards the research proposal -&amp;gt; also on first chapter
Reading: - trying to identify difficulties / issues in modelling applied ecological problems in general - e.g. projecting performance of conservation actions, building the evidence base in restoration ecology as new techniques emerge.
-&amp;gt; aims, trying to identify why reproducibility is important for ecological models / DSTs
defining reproducibility for ecological models (still need to justify this)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>