<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Accuracy on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/accuracy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Accuracy on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/accuracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Baranyi and da Silva (2017) The use of predictive models to optimize risk of decisions</title>
      <link>/posts/baranyi-and-da-silva-2017-the-use-of-predictive-models-to-optimize-risk-of-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/baranyi-and-da-silva-2017-the-use-of-predictive-models-to-optimize-risk-of-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Application domain: Microbiology decision support for predicting food borne Bacteria growth and reduce the need for microbiological testing. Approach/framework: risk assessment and decision-analytic framework.
Aims and objectives of the paper:
 The focus of this paper is not the above interpreted risk, assigned to an a-posteriori event, but the risk of an a-priory decision, that we also call choice or bet in what follows.
  In this paper we explain, backed by examples, why predictive models should be used in combination with a cost-bene fit assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McPherson et al 2018 A simulation tool to scrutinise the behaviour of functional diversity metrics</title>
      <link>/posts/mcpherson-et-al-2018-a-simulation-tool-to-scrutinise-the-behaviour-of-functional-diversity-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/mcpherson-et-al-2018-a-simulation-tool-to-scrutinise-the-behaviour-of-functional-diversity-metrics/</guid>
      <description>\cite{MEE3:MEE312855}
Problem
More and more indices of diversity are created with time. Accurately quantifying functional diversity is important because we want to know how biodiversity loss affects ecosystem functioning.
Functional diversity is the &amp;ldquo;values and range of functionally important traits in a community&amp;rdquo;.
The authors describe four dimensions to functional diversity:
 functional richness evenness divergence redundancy  And they each characterise how organisms interact with ecosystem functioning.
Although the choice of index should be guided by the functional diversity component of interest, there are multiple indices available for each component, and then there are synthetic indices that summarise all four components as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>