<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conservation on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/conservation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conservation on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/conservation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QRPs Study Planning</title>
      <link>/posts/qrps-study-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/qrps-study-planning/</guid>
      <description>QRPs for non-hypothesis testing research in Ecology and Conservation Decision Making Problem and Background:
The reproducibility literature has focused exclusively on hypothesis-testing, whether that be Bayesian or frequentist. This also applies to initial research focusing on ecology and evolution. However, Fidler (2016) correctly identifies that in applied ecological research, particularly in conservation science, non-hypothesis testing methods, such as decision-theory, cost-effectiveness analysis, optimization and other scientific computing methods are common. These approaches come with their own set of reproducibility issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systematic review methodologies for conservation and ecology</title>
      <link>/posts/systematic-review-methodologies-for-conservation-and-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/systematic-review-methodologies-for-conservation-and-ecology/</guid>
      <description>Systematic Review Methods Nakagawa and Poulin [-@Nakagawa:2012fl] recommend following the PRISMA statement, at least for meta-analyses in ecology and evolution.
PRISMA
Checklist here: http://www.prisma-statement.org/documents/PRISMA%202009%20checklist.pdf
Cochrane Review
Manual broken down into two phases of the review: 1. Developing Protocol of the review 2. Conducting Review
Writing review protocol - Formulating review questions, predefining objectives. - Medicine focused, emphasis on reporting adverse effects, on consumer needs - Choosing &amp;lsquo;outcomes&amp;rsquo;of interest (Mandatory). Assessing risk of bias of studies included in the review.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>