<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Reproducibility on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/computational-reproducibility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computational Reproducibility on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/computational-reproducibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ropensci</title>
      <link>/posts/ropensci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/ropensci/</guid>
      <description>Problem Replication effort:
There are many sources of error (as to why claim is not supported, or approximate result[significance in same direction, effect size]):
 actual data is not reflected in code files Can’t match the environment: Missing packages etc, etc, etc  One model of addressing these issues is using Docker:
Docker goes some way to solving this…. BUT: It’s really hard to get docker up and running - you need specialised knowledge of how to get your code and data etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose your own adventure: researcher degrees of freedom and questionable research practices in ecological modelling for decision support</title>
      <link>/posts/modelling-workflows-researcher-degrees-of-freedom-and-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/modelling-workflows-researcher-degrees-of-freedom-and-transparency/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Initial meta-science research in ecology and evolution suggests that the discipline is not immune to the sorts of reproducibility issues highlighted in other scientific disciplines, such as Psychology and Medicine. A recent study has revealed rates of self-reported Questionable Reserach Practices (QRPs) in ecology and evolution comprable to other disciplines. QRPs include practices such as cherry-picking, p-hacking and hypothesising after results are known (HARKing), and result in low rates of reproducibility, contributing to biased accounts of the subject domain in the body of literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Blischak reproducibility and workflowr</title>
      <link>/posts/john-blischak-reproducibility-and-workflowr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/john-blischak-reproducibility-and-workflowr/</guid>
      <description>Institutional road blocks against full reproducibility - methods sections are insufficient. But good software practice is helpful for future you, your labmates when you leave.
Lowndes et al (2017) Peng et al (2011)
Strategies for computational repro Record computing environment  sessionInfo() ## R version 3.5.1 (2018-07-02) ## Platform: x86_64-apple-darwin15.6.0 (64-bit) ## Running under: macOS 10.14.1 ## ## Matrix products: default ## BLAS: /System/Library/Frameworks/Accelerate.framework/Versions/A/Frameworks/vecLib.framework/Versions/A/libBLAS.dylib ## LAPACK: /Library/Frameworks/R.framework/Versions/3.5/Resources/lib/libRlapack.dylib ## ## locale: ## [1] en_AU.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>