<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Research Proposal: Reproducibility and Transparency of Decisions in Ecology and Conservation</title>
      <link>/posts/research_proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/research_proposal/</guid>
      <description>Keywords:
 conservation decision-making ecology reproducibility structured decision-making  Introduction Successful biodiversity conservation and management is underpinned by effective and robust decision-making (Mukherjee et al. 2018). Decision-makers are tasked with allocating limited resources in the face of uncertainty about the effectiveness of alternative management interventions, and incomplete or inadequate scientific information. Moreover, environmental decisions often must be made in complex socio-economic and political contexts, with multiple stakeholders and multiple and/or competing objectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Timeline and Milestones</title>
      <link>/posts/phd_timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/phd_timeline/</guid>
      <description>Timeline &amp;lt;iframe src=“https://egouldo.shinyapps.io/shiny_phd_timeline/” style = &amp;quot;border: none; width: 900px; height: 1000px&amp;gt;
 Milestones Milestones are documented in the RHD manual, page 4: https://app.lms.unimelb.edu.au/bbcswebdav/pid-6166800-dt-content-rid-24849943_3/orgs/COM_01654/RHD%20Handbook%20v%202017%2008%2016%20LMS%20version%202.pdf
Candidature and Confirmation: Probationary Candidate: You start your PhD as a probationary candidate and within 12 months (we recommend the ideal time of 9 to 10 months) you will go through the confirmation procedure, formalising your candidature. Purpose of Confirmation: The main purpose of the confirmation process is to determine if you have developed a detailed research plan together with your supervisor(s), to assess whether this research plan meets the requirements of the degree, and to assess if adequate progress has been made.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>