<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Decision Science on Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/decision-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Decision Science on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/decision-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Baranyi and da Silva (2017) The use of predictive models to optimize risk of decisions</title>
      <link>/posts/baranyi-and-da-silva-2017-the-use-of-predictive-models-to-optimize-risk-of-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/baranyi-and-da-silva-2017-the-use-of-predictive-models-to-optimize-risk-of-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Application domain: Microbiology decision support for predicting food borne Bacteria growth and reduce the need for microbiological testing. Approach/framework: risk assessment and decision-analytic framework.
Aims and objectives of the paper:
 The focus of this paper is not the above interpreted risk, assigned to an a-posteriori event, but the risk of an a-priory decision, that we also call choice or bet in what follows.
  In this paper we explain, backed by examples, why predictive models should be used in combination with a cost-bene fit assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Science Vocabulary</title>
      <link>/posts/decision_science_vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/decision_science_vocabulary/</guid>
      <description>Decision Making: &amp;quot; p.56: For the purposes of this paper, we define decision-making as the process of identifying options and selecting a feasible solution, based on evidence combined with the decisionmaker’s values and experience (DeFries &amp;amp; Nagendra, 2017). – Highlighted 21 May 2018&amp;quot; (Mukherjee et al. 2018)
When is a tool a tool or a system? See heading “decision support systems” in (Dicks, Walsh, and Sutherland 2014) Dicks, L. V., Walsh, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gardner et al. 2018 Decision Complacency and Conservation Planning</title>
      <link>/posts/gardner-et-al-2018-decision-complacency-and-conservation-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/gardner-et-al-2018-decision-complacency-and-conservation-planning/</guid>
      <description>Gardner et al. (2018) add to knowledge-doing gap literature by defining and exemplifying what they call “Decision Complacency”
 The non-use of evidence or systematic processes to make decisions.
 Contextualising decision complacency in the knowledge-doing gap:
Researcher-practitioner divide: the case where researchers do not meet the needs of practitioners such that the information provided by conservation scientists does not allow decision-makers or practitioners to make sufficiently evidence-based decisions Evidence Complacency: Sutherland and Wordley (2017) describe a different angle of the researcher-practitioner divide where practitioners don’t use or seek available evidence, and/or don’t test the impact of their actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guerrero et al 2017 Using SDM to set restoration objectives</title>
      <link>/posts/guerrero-et-al-2017-using-sdm-to-set-restoration-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/guerrero-et-al-2017-using-sdm-to-set-restoration-objectives/</guid>
      <description>Guerrero, A. M., Shoo, L., Iacona, G., Standish, R. J., Catterall, C. P., Rumpff, L., de Bie, K., White, Z., Matzek, V., Wilson, K. A. (2017) Using structured decision-making to set restoration objectives when multiple values and preferences exist. Restoration Ecology. 25, 858–865.
Problem: achieving restoration targets is impeded by difficulty in identifying and working towards targets, because objective setting is beset by multiple / conflicting values and preferences, and there are often time-lags in a restoration action and its desired outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>