<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayesian on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</title>
    <link>/tags/bayesian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayesian on Elise Gould: PhD Research Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/bayesian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting 23 August</title>
      <link>/posts/meeting-23-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/meeting-23-august/</guid>
      <description>Tasks from last week: Develop QRP list across all methods. Figure out what is general between each of the methods. Then come up with a list of QRPs specific to the method under consideration. Also think about the overarching decision / analytic process for each of the methods. Could the QRP occur at multiple points along the workflow / model building pipeline? Sampling protocol - begin writing code, journal selection. Think about elicitation measures, what they could be, and how they could be the same across each of the methods  Other things to discuss today:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simonsohn (2014) </title>
      <link>/posts/simonsohn-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>elise.gould@unimelb.edu.au (Elise Gould)</author>
      <guid>/posts/simonsohn-2014/</guid>
      <description>Relationship to frequentist analyses, and the potential for P-hacking Simsonohn (2014) ran two computational experiments looking at the effects of p-hacking practices on the chance of a type I error for both Bayesian confidence intervals and Bayes Factors. He compared the Bayesian methods to the frequentist methods for each.
Bayesian confidence intervals are mathematically equivalent to frequentist confidence intervals. The only real difference is that their philosophical interpretation is different (and under both inference frameworks, normality is assumed).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>